I have folks it's met again and what
我有乡亲又遇见了什么
we're gonna do now is actually sort of
我们现在要做的实际上是
wrap up our discussion of coalitional
结束我们对联盟的讨论
games and allocating value among the set
游戏和在集合中分配价值
of individuals and we're going to do so
的个人，我们将这样做
by looking at a particular example which
通过看一个特定的例子
we can do some comparison say of the
我们可以做一些比较的说法
core and the Shapley value and and see
核心和Shapley的价值和看
exactly what's going on so let's let's
到底发生了什么，所以让我们
look at a very interesting one so think
看一个很有趣的东西，所以想
about the yeren UN Security Council so
关于耶伦联合国安理会
the United Nations has a Security
联合国有一个安全
Council which makes a whole series of
理事会使整个系列
passes often resolutions among doing
在做事时经常通过决议
other things which can can be very
其他事情可能会非常
important in international politics and
在国际政治中很重要
in particular there are 15 members of
特别是有15个成员
the UN Security Council at present how
目前联合国安理会如何
does this work
这项工作吗
there's five permanent members of the
有五个常任理事国
council so those are China France Russia
理事会，所以这些是中国法国俄罗斯
the UK and the US and so the the they're
英国和美国，所以他们是
always in the Security Council there are
安全理事会中总是有
10 temporary members so beyond these
10个临时成员
five there are other members that rotate
五有其他成员旋转
in and out of the Security Council but
进出安全理事会，但
are chosen in general from the UN and
通常是从联合国和
the ones were a very important aspect of
这是一个非常重要的方面
this is that the five permanent members
这是五个常任理事国
can veto resolutions okay so basically
可以否决决议，所以基本上
if you want to pass something within the
如果您想在
Security Council the five permanent
安理会五个常任理事国
members actually have to agree to it
成员实际上必须同意它
there's some subtleties in this it can
它可以有一些微妙之处
be that they can abstain but ignoring
因为他们可以弃权，却无视
abstention that you basically have to
弃权，你基本上必须
have them on board if any one of them
如果他们中有任何人，请把它们放在船上
says no to something it won't pass in
对不会通过的内容说不
the Security Council but the 10 the 10
安理会，但10到10
other members do not have vetoes okay so
其他成员没有否决权，所以
if we start thinking about a cooperative
如果我们开始考虑合作社
game to capture this and the Security
游戏来捕捉这一点和安全
Council can use different rules for
理事会可以使用不同的规则
voting sometimes they use majority rule
有时他们使用多数制投票
sometimes a two-thirds rule and so forth
有时是三分之二的规则，依此类推
but we'll look at a situation where
但我们会考虑一种情况
they're using majority rule so if we
他们使用多数统治，所以如果我们
want to represent that as a cooperative
想代表合作社
game in order to come to a resolution
游戏以解决问题
what's going to have to be true
什么将是真实的
so if we think about the you know
所以如果我们考虑一下
labeling say China France Russia UK and
标签说中国法国俄罗斯英国和
us as as individuals or players 1 2 3 4
我们作为个人还是参与者1 2 3 4
5 then what's true about the value of
5那么，什么是真正的价值
the coalition so a value of a coalition
联盟是联盟的价值
a coalition can pass legislation or pass
联盟可以通过立法或通过
a resolution in this case and get a
在这种情况下的解决方案，并获得
value of 1 so let's say 1 is success you
值1，所以说1是成功的你
you pass a resolution you can do that if
您通过了一项决议，如果
all five are on board so you need the
所有五个都在船上，所以您需要
five permanent members plus you need a
五个常任理事国加上您需要一个
majority so you need at least half of
多数，因此您至少需要一半
the 15 so you need at least eight
15，所以您至少需要八个
members in total to vote yes to
共有成员投票赞成
overwhelm the other seven that might be
压倒了其他七个可能
voting no but all five of this these
投票否，但所有这五个都投票
have to be present and if you have a
必须在场，如果你有一个
coalition that wants to pass the
想要通过的联盟
resolution that does not include some of
分辨率不包括
these members or falls short of the
这些成员或达不到
eight then you get zero okay so this is
八，那么你得到零好吧，这是
a cooperative game it's a very
合作游戏，这是一个非常
particular one and we can analyze then
特定的，然后我们可以分析
what are the core of allocations for
分配的核心是什么
this what's the Shapley value and so
这是Shapley的值，所以
forth so in order to do that let's start
为了做到这一点，让我们开始
with a simple three player game that has
一个简单的三人游戏，
a similar structure okay and what's the
类似的结构还可以，这是什么
structure of this this is sort of a
这个的结构有点像
simplified version of the UN Security
联合国安全简化版
Council say one permanent member with a
理事会说一名常任理事国
veto and two temporary members and we
否决权和两名临时成员，我们
still operate by majority rule
仍按多数规则运作
so what's true is the value of a
所以真正的价值是
coalition is one if you've got one as a
如果您有一个联盟，那么联盟就是一个
member and you've got at least two
成员，您至少有两个
members on board so if at least two
成员，所以如果至少有两个
agree and one person won't player 1 is
同意，一个人不会成为玩家1
one of them you get it you can pass
其中之一，您可以通过
something otherwise you can't okay so
否则你就不能这样
that's a simplified version but it has
这是一个简化的版本，但它具有
the same kind of structure as the UN
与联合国的结构相同
Security Council so what happens let's
安全理事会，那么发生什么事，让我们
start with the core and try to analyze
从核心开始，并尝试分析
this so we've got our game that V is 1
这就是V等于1的游戏
if if you've got one in there and at
如果你在那里有一个
least two members otherwise you get 0 so
至少两个成员，否则您将获得0，所以
now what does the core has to satisfy
现在核心需要满足什么
remember the core has to be allocating
记住核心必须是分配
each coalition a total that's at least
每个联盟的总数至少为
what it gets so that means that if you
它得到什么，这意味着如果你
put what 1 & 2 to get
把什么1和2得到
they can generate a value of one so they
他们可以产生一个值，所以他们
have to be getting at least one one in
必须至少有一个
three together have to be getting a list
三个在一起必须得到一个清单
one one two and three together have to
一一二和三在一起
be getting one right so we're dividing
得到正确的，所以我们正在分裂
up the total value among the three
三者之和
members and it has to be that that
成员，必须是
everybody gets at least zero since you
每个人至少得到零，因为你
could generate zero but you can't be
可以产生零，但你不能
forced in this case to participate okay
在这种情况下被迫参加
so now when we think about what the core
所以现在当我们考虑核心
is going to do when we want to look at
当我们想看的时候要做
this the the fact that one and two have
这是事实，一个和两个有
to be getting at least one and the total
得到至少一个和总数
of all three have to be equal to one and
所有三个中的一个必须等​​于1并且
nobody can get a negative value that
没有人能得到一个负值
these together imply that X of three
这些都暗示着X等于三
sorry X sub 3 has to be equal to zero
对不起X sub 3必须等于零
right so there's no way to be giving one
对，所以没有办法给予
into at least one and all three a total
分成至少一个和全部三个
of one and except by giving three zero
1的和，除以3为零
okay so then we can do the same thing
好吧，那么我们可以做同样的事情
here that means that X 2 is equal to
这意味着X 2等于
zero if we've got X 2 equals zero and X
如果我们有X 2等于零并且X则为零
3 equal to zero that's going to imply
3等于零意味着
that X 1 has to be one so in this case
X 1必须是1
the fact that 1 is a vital player an
1是至关重要的参与者
essential player
基本球员
this means that the core actually gives
这意味着核心实际上
one the full value here now if you do
如果您这样做的话，现在就在这里获得全部价值
the core for the the Security Council
安全理事会的核心
there with a full 15 members you can
那里有15名成员，您可以
work through that what are you going to
通过工作，你要去做什么
get you're going to get that essentially
得到你将基本上得到
the division of the full value is going
全部价值的划分正在进行
to end up going completely to the five
最终完全进入五个
permanent members so you're going to get
常任理事国，所以您将获得
the five permanent members X 1 through X
X 1至X的五个常任理事国
5 getting a value of 1 and then
5取值为1，然后
everybody else getting a value of zero
其他人都得到零值
but you could have many different ways
但是你可以有很多不同的方式
of allocating that amount in between
在这之间分配的金额
those members and still be in the core
这些成员，仍然是核心
okay so simple idea of what the core is
好吧，核心概念很简单
in this game
在这个游戏中
okay now let's stick with the same game
好吧，让我们继续玩同样的游戏
and do the Shapley value so if we're
并做Shapley值，所以如果我们
looking at the Shapley value for this
看这个的夏普利价值
game what are we going to end up with
游戏，我们最终会得到什么
well we can do our calculations from
好吧，我们可以从
from the the Shapley value we know that
从Shapley值我们知道
the value of I is a given according to
I的值是根据
this formula and in this in particular
这个公式，尤其是这个
you know we can sort of just build this
你知道我们可以建立这个
up we could build it up by first putting
我们可以先放起来
in 1 then 1 2 then 1 2 3 1 1 3 1 2 3 2
合1然后1 2然后1 2 3 1 1 3 1 2 3 2
first then 1 3 first or 2 first then
首先然后1 3首先或2首先然后
oops
哎呀
then then 3 3 and 1 3 then 2 etc and in
然后3 3和1 3然后2等
this case when one comes in these two
这两种情况中的一种
they add nothing and in every other case
他们什么也没添加
no matter where one comes in the 1 comes
无论一进一出
in when there's at least one other
当至少有一个
player there in this in all these other
其他所有玩家
cases they're adding a value of 1 so
情况下，它们的值是1，所以
this is going to tell us that the value
这将告诉我们价值
2 1 should be equal to 2/3 because 2/3
2 1应该等于2/3，因为2/3
of the time they're adding a value of 1
他们添加值1的时间
and 1/3 of the time they're adding a
他们有1/3的时间在添加
value of 0 ok if you go through these
如果您经过这些，则值为0好的
kinds of calculations you can you know
您可以知道各种计算
you've got this weighted by 2/6 this
您已经将此加权为2/6
weighted by 1/6 despite weighted by 1/6
加权为1/6，尽管加权为1/6
and so forth so what you're going to end
等等，你要结束什么
up with this here 2/3 then 2 is going to
在这里2/3然后2将
get 1/6 3 is going to get 1/6 and so
得到1/6 3将得到1/6等等
forth and so what we end up with is
等等，所以我们最终得到的是
Shapley value of 2/3 for one one six for
每1的六分之一的Shapley值
each of the other players so the core
其他每个玩家都是核心
and the Shapley value in this case are
和在这种情况下的Shapley值是
both unique and they're giving us
既独特又给我们
different predictions one the core is
不同的预测之一是
saying everything should go to person 1
说一切都应该归人1
the Shapley value says well 2 & 3
Shapley值表示2和3
actually do generate some value and we
实际上确实产生了一些价值，我们
should be giving them some of the fruits
应该给他们一些水果
of their production
他们的生产
and in this case one is more important
在这种情况下，一个更重要
so they get more but two and three are
所以他们得到更多，但是两个和三个是
still valuable members in this society
在这个社会中仍然是有价值的成员
and the shap we value reflects that but
我们重视的形状反映了这一点，但
these are very different logics you
这些是非常不同的逻辑
might think of the core in a situation
可能会想到情况中的核心
where people might secede and one could
人们可能会分离而一个人可能会分离
walk away and say you know without me
走开，说你知道没有我
you get nothing
你什么也没得到
whereas the Shapley value is doing
而Shapley值正在做
calculations based on marginal
基于边际的计算
contributions okay in terms of
就以下方面而言，捐款还可以
cooperative games then what have we done
合作游戏然后我们做了什么
we've looked at modeling fairly
我们已经公平地考虑了建模
complicated multilateral bargaining
复杂的多边谈判
settings you know something like the UN
您知道诸如联合国之类的设置
Security Council something like that uh
安全理事会这样的事情
and we you know the idea of part of the
我们知道一部分的想法
idea behind cooperative game theory is
合作博弈理论背后的思想是
that you know we could do everything as
你知道我们可以做的一切
a non cooperative game we could have
我们可以拥有的非合作游戏
written down a normal form game for
写下用于
bargaining or we could have written down
讨价还价，否则我们可能会写下来
a giant extensive form for how the
巨大的广泛形式
Security Council and who can bring in a
安全理事会，谁可以带来一个
resolution and then who has to vote yes
决议，然后谁必须投票赞成
and how it all works and then calculate
以及它如何运作，然后计算
what a Nash equilibrium of that game is
那场比赛的纳什均衡是什么
or sub game perfect equilibrium and then
或子博弈完美平衡，然后
try and figure out what the payoffs are
尝试找出收益是什么
and the idea of a cooperative game
和合作游戏的想法
theory is sometimes you want to model
理论有时是您要建模的
things in a more compact way and
事情以更紧凑的方式
actually trying to model an extensive
实际上试图建立一个广泛的模型
form for that bargaining process would
讨价还价表格
be overwhelming and this is a different
势不可挡，这是不同的
way of approaching things which takes an
处理事物的方式
X u Matic approach a very simple
X u Matic的方法非常简单
approach and ends up you know generating
方法并最终导致您知道生成
predictions and there's a number of
预测，并且有很多
different solutions that people have
人们有不同的解决方案
used so you know that you can do core
用过，所以你知道你可以做核心
based ideas Shapley value there's other
Shapley重视其他想法
solutions as well so there's a fairly
解决方案，所以有一个相当
rich literature on cooperative game
关于合作博弈的丰富文献
theory that's based on on different
基于不同的理论
approaches to characterizing what fare
表征票价的方法
kinds of values are
各种价值是